Guide to the Hedley Gordon Graham papers, 1925-1983
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Hedley Gordon Graham papers
1925-1983
C0240
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
3.0 linear feet (4 boxes)
The Hedley Gordon Graham papers contains a scrapbook, acting classes grade books, family photographs and photographs of Federal Theatre Project productions, correspondence, playbills, cards (possibly used for a treasure hunt game), scripts, and magazine and newspaper articles. Federal Theatre material includes photographs, newspaper clippings, and scripts for productions of O Say Can You Sing, Triple A Plowed Under, Altars of Steel, and Living Newspaper productions in Chicago.
Graham, Hedley Gordon
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by W. H. Crain at the University of Texas in May 1988.
Biographical note
Gordon Hedley Graham was a drama major at Columbia University and graduated from the American Academy of Dramatic Arts in 1925, he also spent a year at the Royal Academy of London and a year at the Max Reinhardt School of Drama in Salzburg, Austria.
Professional experience includes working for the Theatre Guild in New York City as an Actor, Stage Manager, and Director of Understudies; work in Hollywood for MGM and Warner Brothers, as well as work in New Orleans. For the Federal Theatre Project he worked as the Assistant Executive Director of the I6 states and directed The Living Newspaper Theatre in Chicago for two years. He also taught at a variety of institutions including the American Academy of Dramatic Arts, Adelphi College, Columbia University, Warner Brothers, Easthampton School of Rhythmics (which he also owned), and the Theatre School of Drama at Carnegie Hall.
Scope and Content
The Hedley Gordon Graham papers contains a scrapbook, acting classes grade books, family photographs and photographs of Federal Theatre Project productions, correspondence, playbills, cards (possibly used for a treasure hunt game), scripts, and magazine and newspaper articles. Federal Theatre material includes photographs, newspaper clippings, and scripts for productions of O Say Can You Sing, Triple A Plowed Under, Altars of Steel, and Living Newspaper productions in Chicago.
The collection is divided into two series.
Series one consists of documents and photographs and is organized alphabetically.
Series two consists of oversize materials including three portrait photographs, a diploma, and a scrapbook.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by folder title.
Series 1: Documents and Photographs, 1920s-1983 (Boxes 1-3)
Series 2: Oversize, 1920s-1930s (Box 4)
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as numerous other personal papers.
Index Terms
Persons:
Graham, Hedley Gordon.
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
New Deal, 1933-1939.; Performing arts.; Theater--United States.
Contents List
- Series 1: Documents and photographs, 1920s-1980s
  Series one contains acting classes grade books, family photographs and photographs of Federal Theatre Project productions, correspondence, playbills, cards (possibly used for a treasure hunt game), scripts, and magazine and newspaper articles. This series is organized alphabetically by folder title.
  - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and notes, Federal Theatre Project, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Employment documents; Radio production for Recreation manual; programs, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Living Newspaper programs, May 1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Louisiana trip with Joe Earle, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous: travel related, Long Island Fair, theatre techniques, 1931-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Federal Theatre Project
  - Newspaper clippings, 1943-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notebook of song lyrics, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Acting class and record books
  - O Say Can You Sing lyrics, circa 1930s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes photocopies of lyrics to the songs "I could go for you," "O say can you sing," "The show must go on," and "When we're out of the red and into the blue."
  - Photographs, circa 1920s-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Personal photographs and Federal Theatre Project related. Altars of Steel in Atlanta and the Living Newspaper production 1935.
  - Photographs: O Say Can You Sing (1 of 2), December 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: O Say Can You Sing (2 of 2), December 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Triple A Plowed Under, March-May 1936 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Triple A Plowed Under, March-May 1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Playbills and programs, 1928-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scripts, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scripts (published), 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scripts: Triple A Plowed Under, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Treasure Hunt game (index cards), undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Oversize, 1920s-1930s
  Series two consists of three large portrait photographs, a diploma, and Hedley Gordon Graham's Federal Theatre Project related scrapbook. This series is organized alphabetically.
  - Diploma from the Academy of Dramatic Arts, 1925 (Box 4)
  - Three oversize portrait photographs, circa 1930s (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)